Chapter 4: The Work Of A Court Magician

Having a conversation with a princess doesn’t change your everyday life.

I still had to wake up early, go to my office, and work everyday. Most of my job involved preparing and organizing documents, so I rarely went out to do anything hands-on. We were no longer in a time of war, after all.

“It’s so different from how people portray it.”

I grumbled. It was a far cry from what I had imagined before becoming a court magician.

In my head, magicians dressed in brilliant robes strutted around the royal palace in a dignified manner, and whenever the country was in danger, they rushed forward to save the day. My colleagues were top-notch magicians and great role models, both noble and admirable.

But reality was different.

We organized documents for meetings, maintained public order by patrolling the royal capital, and conducted magic combat drills to prepare us for emergencies. That was about it.

Most of my fellow magicians looked tired, sleepy, and unhealthy as they trudged along in the palace. Sometimes they seemed like they were about to collapse. It was worrying. Some questioned whether or not I was good enough to follow in their footsteps, but most people treated me kindly, probably because I was the youngest and unintimidating. I think.

The sun was a little west of its noon peak, and I was at a training ground in the western area of the royal palace with Elt-san, a senior in my department. He wore a magic robe, his work uniform, and pointed a red wand toward the sky.

Fire Attribute Mid-Range Advanced Magic—Flame Dragon.

Even in the royal capital, only the best magicians could use this magic. The flame dragon ascended high into the sky and exploded into a gust of hot air. The power, speed, and amount of magic were all superb.

“I expected no less, Elt-san.”

“Everyone in our department can do magic like this.”

While combing his fingers through his short crimson hair, Elt-san brought a water flask to his mouth.

He could use advanced magic of this level… That’s a court magician for you.

“People in our department are really skilled at magic.”

“Rather, there’s no way anyone who’s below average would be hired. I usually do menial chores, but we do have a minimum requirement.”

“I haven’t been assigned any field work, so to me, it seems like my chores are my real job.”

“Not really. The management is just giving us those chores since we wouldn’t have much to do otherwise. Alright, it’s your turn.”

Elt-san left the center of the training ground and stood in the shade of a tree. I’m in trouble.

“I’m not that good at standard magic.”

“Well, give it a try. Even if you’re not good at it, can you do some short-range intermediate magic?”

He spoke with a smile, but I felt uncomfortable.

There are different types of magic, each classified by attribute: fire, water, wind, earth, light, darkness, void; effective range: short, medium, long; and mastery: elementary, intermediate, advanced, superior.

Among magicians, effective range is often more important than attribute, so most magicians focus on expanding their range.

In general, medium-range magic goes several times farther than short-range, and most magicians are familiar with spells at these two distances. Court magicians, of course, are held to higher standards.

Finally, we have long-range magic.

Magic of this type travels extremely far, but its energy must be compressed to do so, and the power becomes weaker as a result. Furthermore, since accuracy becomes an issue at this range, the magician must maintain visual enhancement, a short-range intermediate spell.

The point is, magic is complex. There’s no limit to what you can do or learn.

“…Ice Mist.”

Unenthusiastically, I cast a water attribute short-range elementary spell. A light frost appeared at my feet and spread an unimpressive distance.

Elt-san sighed.

“You’re good at everything except basic magic, Raize.”

“I’m bad at what I’m bad at. It can’t be helped.”

“I can’t believe that the range of your elementary magic is this short. With your magic, even novices wouldn’t be able to freeze anything in the royal palace, you know?”

“I wouldn’t even if I could!”

Feigning offense, I stepped into the shade of a tree, stomping on the frozen ground.

I wish I could say I was entirely joking. I’ve always been bad at most common spells… To be honest, it could be frustrating sometimes.

Elt-san may have sensed my displeasure, because he bought me tea on the way back to my office.

***

There is a bizarre sight in the royal capital that can’t be seen anywhere else.

Mirrors of various sizes, large and small, are installed on the roofs of buildings in the royal capital.

They were originally questioned by citizens, but the royal palace described them as aids for slaying monsters outside the city, and soon people more or less forgot about them.

Of course, there were questions about how exactly it helped… but the results were clear, so no one opposed it directly.

It was the morning after my training session with Elt-san.

The sun had not yet risen, but I was on my way to the annex of the royal palace. The sound of my footsteps echoed throughout the deserted building.

I was shivering. Magicians don’t normally use magic to control air temperature, so I had goosebumps all over.

The interior of the building was illuminated with light magic, and I could see my breath turn white when I exhaled. The temperature was almost certainly below freezing.

“Why do I have to do this…”

I muttered to myself as I climbed the stairs.

There was a reason why I was here so early in the morning.

It was part of my job as a court magician.

Early every morning, I had to perform a certain task on the roof of the annex. This was the tallest location in the city, and you could see far beyond the capital borders. The view was amazing.

But of course, my job wasn’t to look at the scenery every day. It was simple but troublesome.

After climbing all the stairs, I opened the door to the roof. The air that blew in added a wind chill factor to the already cold weather. Although the actual temperature may not change, the presence of wind can drastically alter how cold a person feels.

“I’ll wrap it up quickly and go back to sleep.”

Yawning, I moved to the edge of the roof. I drew my rapier from its scabbard on my waist, and the scraping of metal let out a high-pitched metallic noise. The iron blade shone blue.

“Let’s see… anyone out there?”

Short-Range Intermediate Magic—Visual Enhancement.

The spell focused my vision and allowed me to see much farther than I could normally. A person reading a newspaper near the cafe. An old man sweeping the entrance. And even farther away—a dozen or so monsters approaching from the forest outside the capital.

These kinds of monsters were ferocious and had an appetite that left nothing of their prey. They were different from common creatures and had magical stones embedded in their bodies.

Above all, they were strong. If an ordinary person with no magical ability were to encounter them, he or she would almost certainly die. They attacked humans indiscriminately.

The moment you discover one of them, run away immediately. If you’re slow, you’re done for. But the longer you have to run, the more beasts begin to chase after you, and escape becomes exponentially more difficult.

As a safety measure, court magicians would regularly go out to subdue them.

That is, before I became a court magician.

“~~~ ♪”

While humming a song, I channeled magical power into my blade. The rapier crackled with electric energy, and I flicked it.

“—Blue Lightning.”

The lightning in my rapier manifested into a dozen spears and flew across the city. They ricocheted off the mirrors countless times before striking the monsters I had my eye on. Each one, penetrated by a spear of lightning, collapsed on the ground, spouting purple blood and convulsing violently.

The mirrors could retain magical power and had a special ability to reflect magic.

This was my job every morning.

From the roof of the annex, I could view the outskirts of the royal capital and slay the monsters I saw. Since I took on this role, court magicians no longer had to subdue monsters early in the morning… I was the only one having a hard time. At least I was paid accordingly, but the job reduced my sleeping hours and always left me unbearably tired.

So, in order to secure a second round of sleep—

“Let’s finish this quickly.”

About half an hour later, I hummed as I finished off the last of them.

It’s not that I was slacking off during training the other day. I really am bad at most kinds of magic.

Most, other than a certain kind—by which I mean ultra-long-range magic.

Of all attributes and all classes.

Chapter 5: In Which I Am Forced Into Being An Errand Boy

After finishing my morning duties, I lay on the sofa in my office, giving myself up to fatigue. The soft, white sofa was so comfortable that I could doze off easily. Not that I minded. I could lay here all day, if I wanted to—I already finished today’s work the other day.

As I stared at the ceiling, drowsiness began to cloud my thoughts. Sleeping like this is a privilege granted only to those who wake up early to work. I felt terrible while waking up, but at this moment I was glad I got up early.

In just a few seconds, I would be transported to Dreamland. The trip there was my greatest guilty pleasure. I was lying on what felt like a bed of clouds.

As my mind wandered, my consciousness gradually began to fade…

“—Raize.”

My fading consciousness was suddenly jolted back into existence.

I clicked my tongue, not bothering to hide my displeasure, and gazed at the open door. Who was it? Who could be so audacious as to interrupt my precious morning nap? I was so, so close…

I had a mild urge to send a thunder spear flying into the brain of whoever had opened the door. Of course, it was just an urge.

I scratched my head and sat up.

Standing in front of the door was a woman with golden hair that seemed to shimmer in the light. She shook her hair, which had a single lock dyed green, and turned her emerald eyes towards me. She was breathing heavily. So the perpetrator was—

“Arina-san…”

I rubbed my eyelids lazily and sighed her name.

She was a senior in my department.

In fact, she was the epitome of a nagging senior. She had a lazy atmosphere about her and always treated me like a child. From what I’ve heard, she was frightening when angry, but I had never actually been on the receiving end of her wrath. Conversely, she doted heavily on people when she was in a good mood.

I scowled at Arina-san, who was currently the object of my annoyance.

“…What’s this all of a sudden? I was just about to take a nap.”

“Sorry, but I can’t let you sleep right now.”

“What do you mean?”

In my drowsy mental state, I was struggling to understand the situation. Only something extremely alarming would cause Arina-san to be this impatient… No way—!

“A demon beast appeared—”

“The royal coffee shop Cherry has a new cake on sale! And the stock is limited!”

In my haste and confusion, I almost slipped off my sofa.

“What? Cherry? Cake? You want to eat cherry cake?”

“No. I want to eat the new marron cake that Cafe Cherry is releasing today!”

I still couldn’t quite understand. Why was she so desperate for cake? Is the new cake that amazing? Was my nap interrupted for this? What a waste of time…

While I was assembling my thoughts, Arina-san suddenly approached me and grabbed me by the neck.

“Guh…”

“This is an order. Can you go and buy it right now?”

“If it’s an order, you don’t have to kill me… do you? Don’t grab my neck… it’s supposed to be the shoulders—”

“Sorry.”

When I choked out those words, Arina-san immediately released me. I thought I was actually going to die… Honestly, I wanted to escape right now. But I’ve never been able to escape from her.

“And… Why do you need me?”

“To go get it.”

“Can’t you do that by yourself?”

“I have an errand to run at the orphanage today. I had no choice but to ask someone else. Someone who finishes his work early, is younger than me, and seems easy to handle.”

“Why do you have to go to the orphanage? And wow, that list is pretty specific…”

I stared at her inquisitively, but she didn’t respond.

To this woman, maybe I was no more than a gofer. Well, as a junior in the department, I felt obligated to listen to the demands of my seniors. In fact, I respected them enough to do so.

Well, whatever. Being her errand boy was fine with me, considering I had the time. I could go around the royal capital while I was at it. I still felt sleepy, but that problem would fix itself after a short walk.

“Sure, I can do that. Was it a marron cake?”

“Yes, buy five of them.”

“You can eat that much!?”

How could five cakes fit in such a thin body? I’d be full after just one.

She shook her head.

“Five will be enough for everyone.”

“…Arina-san.”

I relaxed my face.

Usually, she looked tired and indifferent, but at heart she was a genuinely thoughtful person.

Having tea with everyone in the department sounded like a good idea to me. But I’d have to hurry up to get there before the cakes sold out.

“Thanks for thinking about us.”

“Mmm. Right, this should cover it.”

I took the money Arina-san offered me and put it in my wallet. That’s quite a bit of cash… is the cake that expensive? Well, it didn’t matter to me. It’s not my money, after all.

“By the way, would you have gone if I hadn’t agreed?”

“Probably not.”

“Then what would you have done?”

“I’d give you a hard time until you agree.”

She spoke with a straight face.

I take back what I said.

She isn’t kind to me at all. If anything, she enjoys harassing me. It’s terrible.

Chapter 8: A Bout Of Morning Grief

Being a court magician is usually a job to be applied for after graduating from the Royal Grantina Magic Academy, located in the western part of the royal capital. The acceptance rate is extraordinarily low; maybe one in a hundred. Of course, as consolation, those who fail can usually take an examination to become royal palace officials. The working conditions are above average, and the salary is incomparable to that of most other jobs. Of course, the salary of a court magician is even greater.

The majority of court magicians have taken this standard route to where they are today, but this is not the only way.

There is a so-called secret route to becoming a court magician.

In fact, there are multiple, requiring either the recommendation of several current court magicians or a demonstrable ability to perform outstanding feats of powerful magic.

In my case, I was the third kind—I was scouted by the director of the current department for being able to use such outstanding and powerful magic, and became a court magician.

…I say scouted, but it was borderline kidnapping.

Anyways, I’m sorry to those who obtained this job through normal means, but I didn’t take the court magician’s exam, and in fact I didn’t even graduate from the Academy. Frankly speaking, I still can’t believe I’m a court magician.

Until a few months ago, I was hunting demons and selling goods outside the city, and a job like this was inconceivable to me. At the time, my pay was about half of what it is now. With this level of income, I can send a considerable amount of money to my sister.

I have my master to thank for helping me practice my magic. I hope he’s doing well.

The department to which I was assigned is notably special. The faculty is small, and every member is an outstanding magician.

The crux of the matter is this: when I became a court magician, I was forced by the management to undergo a magical operation.

I didn’t know what it meant at first, but after the events of yesterday and today, I understand a little more now.

***

“…”

Roused by the sunlight streaming through my window, I slowly opened my eyes and sat up in my bed. After parting with the princess yesterday, I had returned to my boarding house near the royal palace.

I was never a morning person to begin with, but today was particularly unpleasant.

My body felt sluggish, and my vision went in and out of focus. I was nauseous, and the scars from my operation months ago were burning intensely.

Most of all, I couldn’t quite place the feeling that I had lost something important to me. All that I knew was an uncertain sorrow that gripped my heart.

“…Mana deficiency, I guess.”

Some of these symptoms suggested a dangerously low level of mana in my body. It wasn’t life-threatening, but mana deficiency is a serious affliction for magicians who fight using magic.

Exerting no small amount of effort, I lifted my body out of bed and shuffled into the washroom. After filling the sink with water and splashing my face, I looked at myself in the mirror with newfound clarity.

I almost didn’t recognize the weary face staring back at me. My skin is usually on the lighter end, but right now I was abnormally pale. Meanwhile, dark circles were prominent under my eyes. I thought I’d slept well, but an observer might assume I had pulled three all-nighters in a row.

“…Should I go to work?”

I reached for a towel hanging from the wall to dry my face. After some deliberation, I changed into my uniform.

Before leaving my room, I noticed the scars on my neck glowing faintly before disappearing.

***

“I see. Is this your first time experiencing it, Raize?”

Arina-san and Elt-san were sitting opposite me, on a sofa in my office with tea in their hands.

“That’s tough.”

“It is. My heart hurts like crazy. I seriously wanted to die at first.”

“That being said, you look like you’re struggling to pretend like it’s nothing.”

Trying to act tough wouldn’t work, I guess. Let’s change the subject.

“Why are you both just having tea in my office? Well, I guess it’s my fault for serving it. Neither of you have finished your work yet, I’m guessing?”

“You idiot, I don’t have to work. It’s against my moral code to do anything that seems bothersome.”

“What a way to put it… What about you, Arina-san?”

“You’ll end up doing it for me anyways, right?”

“No way. Take care of it on your own.”

I sighed. To think that they were both older than I was…

“Well, in any case—”

“You’ll do it?”

“I won’t! I still want to know why you’re here.”

“Hey, that’s not how you should speak to your seniors. We came out of worry and the goodness of our own hearts.”

Elt-san chuckled. I wasn’t as amused.

“What, you’re worried?”

“Don’t be so cynical. Your mental state isn’t great, you feel a sense of loss, and your eyes sometimes go out of focus. You haven’t done anything to bring your mana levels down this much, so instead I’m guessing that it caused some sort of forced memory purification.”

“…Why are you never this sharp when you need to be?”

He was clearly contemplating the situation. This was unlike the Elt-san I knew: unscrupulous and a terrible senior.

I felt transparent, but his logic was sound. In fact, having someone to discuss this with made me feel better.

“Could it be the Pledge Geass? It manifests when certain conditions are met.”

“Seems like it. The contract forced upon us is [I don’t remember the name of the royal family]. If you did learn the name, the magic would forcibly erase that memory in your sleep using your own mana.”

“Why is this even a thing?”

“You don’t know, Raize?”

“I don’t.”

Elt-san cleared his throat and began talking.

“During the ancient war, there was a powerful magician in the kingdom. He fought in the front lines, was honored with numerous medals, and contributed greatly to our eventual victory. But when he returned, he was captured by the king under false accusations and sentenced to be burned at the stake. During the execution, he screamed and cursed the king’s name as he died.”

“Sounds like a fairy tale’s tragic ending.”

“But that wasn’t the end. After the magician died, the king was afflicted with great pain for seven days and seven nights. In the end, he went mad and slit his throat with a dagger.”

“So based on that tradition, do you mean these pledges…”

“This pledge is forcibly established upon anybody with exceptional magical power who wishes to enter the royal capital.”

I sipped my tea, hoping it would calm me.

“These people aren’t treated like humans. By these people, I mean us.”

“That’s right. The management doesn’t see us as humans or even magicians. We’re… no more than weapons to them.”

“…”

In a lapse of strength, I sank lower on the sofa.

Now that I thought about it, I didn’t remember the name of Her Royal Highness, which I had learned just yesterday. Did she know about this? Was she so cruel as to ask me to call her by her name, knowing what would come about afterwards?

An inkling of regret wormed its way into my heart. I had no complaints about my job itself. Certainly, being a court magician meant that I was treated well.

But… we’re not weapons. I have emotions. I have character. I have a will of my own. Just like any other human being.

The idea was demoralizing. Maybe I had made the wrong choice back then.

Ah… I want to run away. I don’t want to work.

Arina-san, who was sitting silently in front of me, suddenly stood up and moved to my side.

“Arina-san?”

She didn’t respond to my calling her name. Instead, she wrapped her arms around my slender body. My head rested on something extraordinarily soft.

“There’s nothing to worry about. Not knowing the name of the royal family won’t hurt you.”

“Um…”

“And just so you know, this is something that only the king knows among the royal family. The princess probably isn’t aware. Even the aristocrats who know the story aren’t allowed to discuss it. “

“And somehow you found out?”

“Well, I have my ways.”

Arina-san spoke with confidence, stroking my head.

That’s great and all, but I’d like you to release me before acting all proud. Please, I’m embarrassed about the position I’m in right now.

“Raize, you’re still just a kid.”

“Do you want me to kill you from close range? Please go and finish your work.”

I did have to admit, however, that talking to the two of them helped my emotions settle down. Companionship truly is wonderful.

Also, please let go. Why is this hug starting to feel painful? My bones are creaking!

“You know, you’re surprisingly comfortable to hold.”

This is anything but comfortable! Is this how I die!?

I struggled for another minute, miraculously surviving long enough for her to release me.

I might have developed a new phobia today.

Chapter 9: Changes In the forest

For my own good, I have to stay away from Her Highness.

That was the resolution I made after forgetting her name once.

To that end, I wasted no time returning to my office after my morning duties. I avoided the courtyard during my breaks. In my desperation, I even activated Short-Range Advanced Magic─Invisibility whenever I had to walk inside the royal palace.

I moved while considering as many possibilities as I could. Since my mana levels are considerably higher than average, I didn’t have to worry about running out. The only real danger to my mana was the pledge activating itself again.

Ultimately, it paid off: although I saw Her Highness several times from afar, nothing came of it.

Furthermore, she no longer stared at me randomly. Rather, she looked kind of lonely… Seeing her in that state made me feel apologetic. But I couldn’t afford to risk depleting my mana and losing my ability to fight in an emergency.

As long as I was bound by the pledge, avoiding the royal family was in my best interest.

“…It hurts.”

But ignoring her like this… My chest ached uncomfortably. I had never tried to avoid anyone before.

Milena-san giggled when she saw me brooding over my problems.

“Why are you laughing?”

“Sorry. That’s quite a gloomy face you’re wearing. It’s a new sight to see.”

Milena-san put a hand to her mouth and picked up a pile of documents on the desk in the lounge.

“What I mean is, all of the people in this department are outstanding magicians, right? Maybe it’s because they’re talented, but there are a lot of impulsive kids here. Compared to them, you’re surprisingly in touch with your emotions, Raize.”

“Isn’t this normal? Avoiding people isn’t exactly enjoyable.”

I didn’t think I was especially good-natured or anything, but I generally tried not to offend or hurt others.

A subtle expression flickered over Milena-san’s face.

“What?”

“No, you’re kind and humble. But in my opinion, there’s something else going on here.”

“What is it?”

“It’s best if you find out for yourself… although I’m not sure if you will.”

“Huh?”

Milena-san ignored my questioning look and handed me the documents. The thick pile of papers was tied together with string to prevent it from falling apart.

“What’s this?”

“It’s from yesterday’s executive meeting. As you may know, the number of demons in the outskirts of the royal capital has increased considerably.”

“I had a feeling.”

Every time I was on the roof of the annex, targeting the demons outside the capital borders, I suspected that my job was taking longer than before. Maybe I can get a raise if I petition. I made a mental note to ask later. I couldn’t have my workload increasing this much without any sort of compensation.

“So what do you want me to do?”

“It’s simple. I want you to go with Arina to investigate the outskirts in person. If you figure out what’s going on, you can move at your own discretion.”

“Hold on, isn’t this a job for the Kingdom Knights?”

“We want someone more powerful to go.”

I frowned. I had a lot of questions, but I couldn’t complain. I didn’t have the right nor the achievements to doubt the decisions of my seniors. Nevertheless, there were many things I would rather do than spend my evening in the forest.

“But is it really fine to send me? I’m a fish out of water in short-range battles.”

“That’s not true, I know you can still fight at close range to some extent. But if you’re worried, just let Arina guard you. You can focus on the demons you detect in advance.”

“…All right, then. I’ll head out tonight.”

“Why tonight?”

She probably expected me to go while it was still light out. And in fact I would, if I were alone. But I’m working with Arina-san here.

“She always naps during the day, so she’s more active when it’s dark. It’s pretty clear that she’s stronger, too, based on the mock battles.”

“Oh, that girl’s a night owl… but are you okay with that? Aren’t demons also more active at night?”

“It’s fine. I get stronger too. I’ll finish them all.”

“…Sounds good.”

Milena-san smiled wryly.

I still didn’t know how to interpret the look on her face.

***

“There certainly are a lot of them.”

“That’s why we’re looking into it. I didn’t expect this many of them.”

The sun was setting, and Arina-san and I were investigating the forest bordering the royal capital. The surrounding trees fostered a dense, eerie atmosphere. When the wind blew, the thick foliage rustled noisily.

In a brief moment of respite, I looked around and poked at a demon corpse lying at my feet with a branch.

“Quantity aside, I don’t notice anything strange yet. They’re the same as the ones I shoot from the palace.”

“Still, this number is surprising. It’s been less than an hour since we entered the forest, and we’ve killed at least a hundred.”

“At least we’ll be recovering plenty of magical stones.”

Usually, you would see maybe ten in an hour, even at night. But we had encountered ten times that. No matter how you looked at it, this was abnormal.

—Almost as abnormal as the speed at which Arina-san took care of them. With just a snap of her fingers, a mountain of demons would be pulled underground, never to return.

“That’s an amazing spell.”

“Of course. It’s strong, and it’s also possession magic, so only I can use it.”

With pride, Arina-san tapped her toes against the ground. A nearby tree immediately began to decay, and the sound of its collapse echoed through the woods.

Possession magic is magic that only a particular individual can use. It monopolizes the invocation formula. Compared to universal or general-purpose magic, possession magic is far more powerful. There are very few magicians on this continent capable of using it, and they’re heavily sought after.

“Earth Attribute Mid-Range Superior Magic—Earth Interference. There has to be a limit, right? You’re literally manipulating the earth itself and everything connected to it.”

“This is the power of possession magic. Wouldn’t it be bad if anyone else could use this spell?”

“If you’re ever after me, I’ll be sure to surrender quickly.”

I can’t possibly win. To begin with, I wasn’t a close-range fighter.

They say that beautiful roses have thorns. Well, Arina-san was certainly beautiful, and she’d be a real thorn in the side in a fight—Oh.

“What’s wrong?”

“There are five demons about four hundred meters away. You’ve been doing most of the work so far, so let me take care of them.”

I drew my rapier and pointed it straight ahead. At this distance, I didn’t even need visual enhancement. Needles of lightning, each about the size of an index finger, manifested in the air around me.

“Thunder Needle of Death.”

They shot in the direction I was pointing faster than eyes could follow. The needles struck their target, the magic stones at the heart of each demon. Bullseye.

“They’re dead. I don’t see any others around, so let’s move on. I’d like to return before midnight.”

I led the way ahead of Arina-san.

“…You’re dreadful too, you know? If it came down to a fight, I think I’d be beaten before I could even get close.”

I heard her mutter something behind me, but I couldn’t hear it over the rustling of the trees.

With my rapier sheathed, we forged deeper into the dark forest.

Chapter 12: The Princess Is Not To Be Underestimated

Her Highness stared at me accusingly, but to be honest, I was a bit awestruck by the scenery before me.

The trees swaying gently in the background; the fountain’s soothing ambience; the moon shining directly above us, illuminating our surroundings dense with shimmering vapor; it seemed as if everything existed only to complement the princess’s natural beauty.

But at the end of the day, I was only distracting myself from reality. I needed to say something—anything.

“It’s been a while, huh? What are you doing here in the middle of the night? Staying up late is bad for your skin, right? You should go back and get a good night’s rest.”

“It’s alright. I’m just taking a walk.”

My rapid-fire attempts at guiding her back to her room were shut down effortlessly. I had nothing else to say.

Her Highness’s pout wasn’t a new sight to see, but today, the reason was obvious.

“Raize-sama.”

“Yes?”

“Why have you been avoiding me?”

A sharp pang of guilt struck my heart as I stared into her tearful eyes… But I can’t make any blunders here. I wanted to give her some sort of assurance, but at the same time I couldn’t let this affect my work.

“Are you sure you’re not misunderstanding something? I’ve been stuck in my office for the past few days, that’s all.”

“Don’t lie to me!”

Her voice echoed throughout the garden.

Realistically, there was probably no one else here at this time of night, but that didn’t stop me from wincing at the volume.

I stared at the princess, who was shaking indignantly. She seems sure of herself… What does she know?

“At first I thought you were just busy in your room. But I saw you.”

“Wait a minute. You saw me?”

“I did.”

Impossible. I invoked invisibility while moving between private locations, and I avoided contact with not just Her Highness, but almost everyone outside of my coworkers. My bases were covered.

“When?”

“About three days ago, in the morning. You were casting spells from the roof of the annex. I saw it while I was on a morning walk.”

“That’s quite early for a morning walk…”

I was surprised.

I normally do my morning duties before the sun comes up, when the sky is just beginning to brighten. Most people would be asleep at that hour. Yet… the one person that mattered was not.

Well, I suppose there was no easier time to find me.

The biggest drawback of invisibility is that it can’t be used in tandem with other magic. So of course, I had to remove it every morning while sniping at demons from afar.

I could call it an inevitable Achilles heel, but I’m sure there were ways to get around it. Today as well: if I had simply gone home, Her Highness wouldn’t have found me.

Everything was the product of my own negligence.

I’m sure it was also preemptive karma for my next lie.

“Alright, I’ll come clean. Yes, I’ve been using invisibility while moving around for the last few days, but it’s because of my mission.”

“What do you mean?”

Her Highness’s eyes widened in surprise, and she clasped her hands in front of her. I disliked the idea of deceiving her, but I also wanted to protect her.

“I can’t be specific, but trust me when I tell you that everything is for the sake of my mission. Avoiding you wasn’t my decision. Please understand.”

A half-truth. My mission is to protect the royal capital from demons, so I couldn’t afford to learn the princess’s name and have my mana depleted again. I had no way of dispelling the pledge, and I couldn’t reveal it to the princess, so my solution was to avoid contact with her. There was no better alternative.

But avoiding her was ultimately my own decision, so that part was a complete lie. My conscience punished me with another wave of guilt.

Her Highness, who listened in silence, looked down and closed her eyes.

Did she believe me? If that were enough, then maybe I didn’t have to do all this in the first place—

“Seventy percent truth… and thirty percent lies.”

“What?”

Did I hear her correctly? Her unwavering confidence once again took me by surprise.

Her Highness slowly opened her eyes and gazed at me. Her eyes, normally silver, were a vivid sky blue. That’s… no way.

“Magic?”

“Yes. Short-Range Superior Magic—Mind’s Eye. It’s possession magic that lets me see through the minds of people and their essence. Naturally, that includes truth and lies.”

“Possession magic…”

My initial state of shock was wearing down, and I could think more clearly now. The princess had possession magic? Moreover, the ability to see through people… It wouldn’t help much on a battlefield, but in a sense it was probably the most useful ability I’ve seen so far.

“I’m sorry. I can’t believe you could use possession magic… and I’m also sorry for telling you a lie, if only a small one.”

“I don’t mind. Did you perhaps lie out of concern for me?”

“…………I am deeply grateful to you for your kindness.”

She hit it on the nose. I didn’t want to—no, I couldn’t cause her any trouble. As a court magician serving under the royal family, I needed to set my priorities straight.

Her Highness smiled and took a step towards me.

“I forgive your lies, Raize-sama. Rather, I’m sorry that you must be burdened for my sake. And thank you very much.”

“No, it’s part of my role as—”

“But…”

Cutting me off, Her Highness leaned in and put her finger on my chest, just above my heart.

“Be more careful, okay?”

“…Yes.”

Although the princess’s mouth was smiling, her eyes were not. The glint in her eye was more menacing than beautiful. And her finger looked like it could go through my wildly beating heart at any moment.

Where was the quiet and bashful princess I knew before?

As I pondered this question, I returned an awkward smile at the girl in front of me.

Chapter 15: Premonition.

Early morning, the next day.

Unlike most days, when I would be racing back to my office from the annex to squeeze in a nap before the work day officially began, I was in no such hurry today. My back rested on the wall and I was lost in thought. As always, my rapier hung from my waist, and I was wearing a black robe: proof of my position as a court magician.

I wore this same uniform every day, but on this particular occasion there was a small difference.

“Isn’t this too much responsibility for me…?”

I sighed and hung my head. My fingers went to a brooch, decorated with gold roses, on my chest.

“It’s weird that they’re leaving this to a newcomer. Even if my role is a bit more hands-off, there are loads of knights more suitable for the task…”

One by one, the thoughts running through my head spilled from my mouth, relieving some of the pressure I had been feeling. But it was nowhere near gone.

“Haah… Why am I like this?”

All this sighing and mumbling might have been rude, but I didn’t care. Right now, I was the only person here, and only the clouds looked down upon me.

As the sky brightened, I thought back to yesterday.

***

“On the day of the Founding Festival, you are to be the shadow guard of Her Royal Highness the princess.”

“The shadow guard?”

I repeated the phrase curiously. Shadow guard… What is that? Surely my job wasn’t to watch the princess’s shadow. Just kidding. I had a rough idea of what it meant, but I couldn’t be too sure.

“Why do they need me to guard the princess? Aren’t there already court magicians assigned to escort her?”

“Of course there are. Five, in fact.”

“Then—”

“But not all of them are cut out for fighting if it comes to it.”

“Huh?”

Anyone who can become a court magician should be skilled enough, I thought. Seeing my confusion, Milena-san explained politely.

“It’s true that court magicians are among the strongest people in the kingdom. That won’t change. But not everyone is trained specifically to fight. Most people who pass the court magician’s exam, even after years of training, are sent to departments where they lose practice. They want someone who has a good track record in terms of battle.”

“And that’s why someone from our department has to hide from the shadows.”

Elt-san sat on the sofa and slouched lazily.

Her Highness is a very important figure, so I guess it makes sense… By the way, I still have a bone to pick with you, Elt-san. You’re acting awfully comfortable for someone who left me on my own, aren’t you? I admit, I would have been in an even worse situation without you, but this and that are two different matters, right?

I decided now wasn’t the time to bring it up.

“Aren’t Elt-san or Arina-san more suitable, then? They’re unmatched when it comes to anything close-range.”

The only short-range magic I’m comfortable with is either elementary, or a utility or support spell. My swordsmanship and physicality were no better than that of an average knight. I didn’t see why there was any reason to pick me.

“They’re stronger in close combat, but you have to remember that we’ll be in the busiest areas of the royal capital. I can’t have them acting as they normally do elsewhere and collapsing the buildings around them. Some Founding Festival that would be.”

“Hey, Chief, that’s a bit much, isn’t it?”

“We know how to control ourselves.”

“Yes, yes, just a little.”

Milena-san turned to me again, ignoring the other two.

“So it turns out that your long-range sniper magic is excellent for this situation. Your precision and tactics far outweigh their firepower. Not to mention, you’ve been getting really good at the invisibility spell recently, haven’t you? You’re the most qualified person in this department!”

She grabbed my hand with enthusiasm. It was hard to say no after her spiel. Not that I could have anyways, as a junior.

“Well, I’ll do my best, but what’s with this shadow guard situation? It would be easier for me to just stick with the main guard.”

“The higher-ups are nosy when it comes to escorts, especially the aristocrats who believe in tradition.”

“I see.”

Some aristocrats were really stubborn. What’s the point of tradition if the royal family is injured due to an insufficient guard?

“So don’t screw up and make them hate you even more, okay? You might find your head cleanly detached from your neck.”

“Don’t end with that!”

***

“…………Hah…”

I sighed again.

It was another sign of my unconfidence. Maybe a perfect shadow guard shouldn’t sigh at his job, but I was only bracing myself for what was to come.

I played with the brooch pinned to my chest.

Made of pure gold, it was a symbol representing the royal guard that all members had to wear. I didn’t see a point in having it, considering I would be spending most of my time invisible, but I was told to wear it anyways.

…This kind of gaudy stuff doesn’t suit me.

“I should be getting going.”

Exiting the roof, I went down the stairs and through the palace hallway. The festival was in four days, but my stomach hurt already. The responsibility… the consequences… A plethora of nasty images ran through my head. I won’t be able to sleep well for a while. This might be grounds for overtime pay.

“Did you hear?”

“Huh?”

I froze. At the end of the hallway, I saw two magicians who seemed to have just arrived at work. They looked like they were in their twenties, and their faces were filled with anxiety.

I quietly cast a spell to raise my hearing and eavesdropped on their conversation. This was by no means a bad thing. It was just information gathering. I should be praised, in fact.

“It seems true. Several court magicians from the royal guard disappeared. The room they were last seen in was covered in bloodstains.”

“How many disappeared?”

“They don’t know yet. But that’s not the worst part. Among the missing wizards was Arsenas, the deputy commander.”

“What!? That’s a big problem!”

They kept talking, but I had heard enough. The pressure from earlier was gone, replaced with a more apprehensive feeling.

I rubbed my chin as I walked to my office.

“…Seems like the Founding Festival won’t end peacefully.”

With a sense of foreboding, I thought about how to best sort things out.

Chapter 16: A Certain Individual's Dream

[TL/ED Note: In Chapter 14 we had that the festival was the 100th year’s celebration, but it turns out it’s actually the 1000th year. This has been corrected.]

The days before the Founding Festival flew by quickly. During this time, the commercial district came alive with the bustle of people preparing food and setting up stalls and tents.

This year marked the 1,000th anniversary, so the citizens were especially enthusiastic. At least I assumed so, given that I had never seen any of the previous years’ festivals.

Of course, they weren’t the only ones getting ready for the coming celebration. The court magicians, knights, and various other court officials all had their schedules full with countless tasks: maintaining logistics for guests, taking preemptive countermeasures in case of a security failure, preparing to host foreign VIPs, and escorting the royal family, to name a few.

The festival hadn’t even started, yet exhausted faces were everywhere.

These past few days were intense for me, too.

“Raize! Go to Central Square in half an hour and shut down the stalls listed here that haven’t been permitted to operate. You have permission to use force.”

“I don’t need that kind of permission, I’ll just warn them!”

“Hey, Raize, I saw an adult Hippogriff flying just now. It might be dangerous if it comes down, so do you think you could get it from here?”

“Can’t you see how busy I am? You do it, Elt-san.”

“You’re the long-distance snipe monster, you do it.”

“I’ve half a mind to punch you ‘accidentally’…”

“Raize, I’m going to take a nap. Wake me up in five hours, exactly. If you’re off by even a little bit, I’ll collapse the ground beneath you.”

“Arina-san, you have work to do! Now’s not the time!”

Etcetera, etcetera.

I was exhausted from being overworked everyday by my boss and seniors and even other departments. Wasn’t my job supposed to be just protecting the princess from the shadows? My to-do list was increasing everyday.

Because of this, I haven’t been able to think about the conversation I heard the other day. Court magicians were disappearing, but apart from Milena-san’s confirmation, I didn’t know much else. Apparently she had received an order to put the Founding Festival first.

I was a bit surprised that they prioritized the celebration over human lives, but I sort of understood now that I had actually participated in the preparation. I had no time to spare thinking about it. A few people were sent to investigate, but any more and the aristocrats would be throwing a fit.

And if you think about what the general population cares about, the answer should be obvious.

What’s more important to most people: the whereabouts of a few magicians or the annual celebration of the kingdom’s founding? The latter, of course. The former doesn’t concern them at all.

And although it concerned me, I had far too many other things to think about. Well, if something ends up happening, I’ll deal with it then.

My break time was just about coming to an end. My communication stone was shining, prompting me to get back to work. That couldn’t have been more than three minutes…

“Why can’t I be done already?”

With a sigh, I made my way back to the hellscape that was festival preparations.

***

Two more days passed, and soon enough it was the day of the Founding Festival—a day to celebrate the anniversary of the founding of the kingdom.

◇

I was dreaming.

It was a recurring dream, one that I remember quite often.

“──”

I trembled with fear in the middle of the forest path, dim in the early morning light.

“Come back into the carriage, Princess!”

A knight turned around, fearing for my safety—and was immediately mauled by more than a dozen demons jumping out from the shadows. He lost consciousness in a heartbeat, and all I could think about was the fact that he did it to protect me—

“Oh my God! These demons are too strong!”

“Endure it! Do something, even if you can only stand in front of the princess!”

The few remaining knights stood firm to protect me, at the risk of their own lives. They wiped their foreheads, smearing blood on some, and gripped their swords.

All I could do was stand there with an overwhelming sense of guilt.

I’m just the princess of some country. I have nothing. But they… they have a noble spirit and an unwavering heart. They have so much to live for.

“Someone… help them.”

I’m sorry. I’m sorry. I’m sorry for not being able to do anything.

I begged for help that would never come. Instead, the only things that came were the anguished yells coming from the knights struggling in front of me.

My eyes locked on the grotesquely bent arm of one knight knocked down by a demon. The white of bone was clearly visible piercing through the arm’s flesh.

Yet, he stood back up. Even with a wound that made me wince and want to avert my eyes, the knight was still trying to protect me. His chivalrous spirit was admirable. It was everything I wished I had at the moment.

I wanted to run, but I couldn’t move my legs. I wanted to fight, but I was weak. Why? Why? Why?

“Ah, ah, ah, aah—“

Crushed by remorse, tears welled up in my eyes.

“Princess, look out!”

“What?”

I turned at the voice, and a winged demon descended from the sky and bared its fangs at me. It was after me—its prey.

…It seemed that I was going to be a worthless princess until the very end.

I relaxed my shoulders, accepting my inevitable death.

At that moment, lightning engulfed the head of the beast and it fell to the ground, dead.

The knights and I could only watch in surprise as the remaining demons around us were struck down by bolts of lightning, one after another. Not a single one missed its target.

In no time, the horde was gone. The knights sat down in fatigue and the magician with us began healing the numerous wounds among them.

Normally, you would run to your savior to thank them and apologize. But I had to use visual enhancement to see where the lightning had come from.

A few seconds later, I saw—

***

“…”

The sun shone through the gaps in the curtains, and I emerged from my dream.

I was no longer in the forest, but in my private room in the royal palace. The morning light reflected from the polished furniture and onto my luxurious bed.

The time… My goodness, I slept in a little.

Today was the Founding Festival, so royal officials would be very busy. That includes me, of course.

Oh, I still had to think about the royal speech I would be giving this evening.

I got out of bed, walked to the window, and fully opened the curtains.

Chapter 17: When I Grow Up, I'd Like To Become A Decent Person

“…I’m tired.”

I croaked out my first two words of the day.

I was both mentally and physically exhausted from all the work I had yesterday, what with my given job and all the other extraneous tasks my seniors had me do for them.

It was different from the time I learned Her Highness’s name. This was just overwork. Rest assured I’ll be fighting for overtime pay.

Even after washing my face, it was painfully obvious that I wasn’t in my best condition. I had no dark circles under my eyes, but I could still see in the mirror just how tired I was.

I combed down my bedhead and changed into my uniform, choosing not to prepare breakfast today. I wasn’t in the mood to eat.

After making myself presentable, I left my house and walked down the main street of the capital. The cloudless sky was a vivid blue, and flashily decorated shops lined the street. It seemed that everyone was looking forward to a busy day of celebration. The past few days were an event all on their own, but today was when they would see their efforts pay off.

Some stalls were preparing food and others were inflating balloons. I took in the sights as I made my way to the royal palace.

My mission today was important: to protect the princess. I had contemplated educating the main guard in real combat, but decided not to. Two days wasn’t enough to learn anything useful. And my job was a support role, anyways.

“You’re always early, aren’t you?”

“Elt-san…”

Patting my shoulder (with his strength, it was closer to a slap) was my senior, Elt-san. He was dressed in his magic robe and his red hair stood out as always.

At a glance everything seemed normal, but looking closer, he seemed under the weather.

“You didn’t get enough sleep?”

“Well, it gets like this every year.”

There were prominent circles under his eyes, and his right eye was visibly bloodshot. That, along with his sunken cheeks, gave the impression that he was ten years older than he really was. Is this what happens every year? He looked like he couldn’t even stand straight… If I didn’t know any better, I would have believed that he was the drunkard I saw in the tavern yesterday who challenged the barkeep and went five rounds.

“So, are you all right?”

“Oh, it’s no problem… just a hangover.”

“So it was you!”

To clarify, the man didn’t just have five drinks. He challenged five people to drinking rounds, and I know this because after going against the barkeep he proudly proclaimed that it was his fifth win. Disgusting.

What are you doing the day before the Founding Festival?

“Raize, you’ll find out when you grow up…”

“Please don’t taint my vision of the future… I feel like throwing up just looking at you. Is this what you meant by ‘it’s like this every year’? You weren’t talking about the overwork?”

“Well, I was working…”

“Oh, get off!”

I shifted myself away from Elt-san, who was trying to lean on me. He didn’t reek of alcohol, but I couldn’t be sure that he wouldn’t puke all over me.

“Now that I think about it, isn’t your home in a different direction? Where did you come from?”

“If I was at home… I would have overslept.”

“You’re saying you stayed up all night? I hope your hangover lasts extra long today.”

“You… since when were you so harsh on me?”

Seeing such a terrible adult would put off anyone.

The royal palace was right in front of us.

I just wanted to hole up in my office for the rest of the day.

***

“You, too!?”

Stepping into the common room, I was greeted by the sight of Milena-san pale-faced and collapsed on a sofa, with Arina-san in a similar state across from her. Between them sat no less than ten bottles of wine.

“Ah… good morning, both of you. It really is a good morning…”

“It looks to me like the worst morning of your life, if I’m being honest with you!”

“Raize… you’re noisy. I’m going to throw up…”

“Why is everyone drinking to the point of being hungover… and also, shouldn’t today be the day you drink? Why did you go all out yesterday?”

Drinking on the night of the Founding Festival is understandable. It’s just participating in the festivities, after all. But the day before… What about your security jobs!?

Milena-san raised herself with some effort and cradled her head in her hands.

“We’re off today…”

“What? No, you guys have to patrol the area, right?”

“Somehow, they let us off. They’re sending some of the royal guards instead.”

“So I drank all night… and here we are. I usually drink after it’s over, but this year it should be fine.”

“Is that so?”

I sort of understood. Elt-san, on the other hand, could not be forgiven. It’s different when you do this every year. No excuses.

I was staring at Arina-san when she suddenly grabbed my arm and pulled me in.

“Uhh, what’s wrong?”

“……“

“What is it?”

When I asked her again, she gripped my arm even harder and looked at me with a dying face.

“Headache pills… Bring me some.”

“You’re supposed to take Eastern medicine for hangovers, not headache pills. Both of you.”

Their eyes begged me for help, and my sense of pity won out. Grumbling complaints under my breath, I went to the medicine cabinet in my office to look for the medicine they needed.

Chapter 26: The Stone Is Struck By The Vindictive Who Persists To The End

“… Huh!”

I jumped and avoided the approaching torrent of light. However, I didn’t end up landing on the roof, but on the stone paving far below.

I immediately applied shock-resistant magic to my legs to soften the impact.

Well, it’s still painful anyway. Even if it’s mitigated, there’s still some impact. And it certainly resonates with the wound.

I checked the surroundings. This place is… good.

I seem to have lost more blood than I thought, and I feel weak.

“Raize-sama!”

Her Highness collapsed on the spot and called out anxiously to me, as I leaned my back against the wall of the house. Well, I’m not the one she should worry about… but it isn’t impossible, right?

Everyone would be worried when they see such a bloody and wounded person. So will I.

“Your Highness, it’s all right, don’t worry. I’m still alive.”

“You don’t look all right!”

She casted a healing spell on me in a hurry. But what matters now is the amount of blood in the body. Even if the wound is sealed by healing magic, the lost blood will not be restored. It may reduce further bleeding, but will not recover any lost blood.

But it’s much better than nothing… Now I can concentrate on my last blow!

“Finger Light Bullet.”

A number of conical lights flew toward Arsenas, who gracefully descended to the ground. It went straight to his heart, since he is distracted by the shock of the fall.

“You’re clever.”

He easily struck them off with a sword. At the same time, Arsenas stepped up forcefully and thrust his sword into my stomach.

“Ah…”

I can feel air gushing out of my throat. The pain spreads throughout my body, and the affected area becomes unusually hot. My vision is getting blurred. I lost even more of my already lessened blood. No wonder.

Her Highness’ screams reach my ears.

“Raize-sama!! Stop it now, Arsenas!”

“Your Highness, this is a battle. There is no mercy.”

My abdomen which is stabbed mercilessly is now overflowing with blood. I feel weak and tired. Even though I’m alive… I feel like I’m half dead. I’ll have to cover the wound little by little so that I won’t die fast.

I guess it’s the first time I’ve been hurt so much. But it can’t be helped. This is my job.

“Now, Your Highness, there’s no one in the way. I’ll take you with me.”

Perhaps he thought I was dead, but Arsenas turned to her and held out his hand.

But the princess glared back at him with sharp eyes.

“Arsenas… why are you doing this?”

“…”

Arsenas put his hand on his chin and thought for a moment, then smiled and opened his mouth.

“Possession magic, Your Highness.”

“What?”

“I… No, my Lord wants the magic formula of your Mind’s Eye Apperception. I’m just carrying out my mission to fulfill their wishes.”

“Lord? He? What are you talking about, Ar? And what’s that pattern on your body?”

“Pattern? How did Your Highness know it? That’s something you shouldn’t know…”

It’s abnormal. It’s obviously getting weird.

As soon as Arsenas began to tell her why he was aiming for Her Highness, he looked as lifeless as those zombies, and an eerie black pattern appeared on his neck hidden in his clothes, crawling down his face. I think that’s a magic formula… I’ve never seen it before, but it’s probably so.

And it’s confirmed.

Arsenas, just like the others, is manipulated. He is unaware of his own physical changes and merely moves to accomplish his commanded purpose.

What bothered me was the purpose of all this.

The aim is possession magic.There is someone called the Lord behind it. Arsenas words suggest that there are more than one of them.There’s a lot to think about…

“Ugh, ack.”

“Still alive…”

He walked toward me again with his sword.

“Too bad, a hole in your stomach alone can’t seem to stop you.”

“Well, I’m dying enough.”

He grabbed me by the collar, put his sword to my neck, and cut my collar.

My white skin is revealed and the magical formula of Pledge Geass on me could be seen. At the sight of it flashing faintly and truly, Arsenas frowned, and Her Highness pressed her mouth and opened her eyes wide.

“This is… a magic formula of oath, but I’ve never seen it before. What’s engraved on it?”

“… I don’t want to answer…”

“I’m curious, but it’s okay.”

He let go of my collar and I fell on my back. The wound in my abdomen gave rise to tremendous pain.

No, that’s far from it now. If I do nothing, my neck will be cut off.

While I was thinking, I heard Her Highness scream again.

“Oh, my God! Stop it! You’re gonna kill him!”

“I’m sorry, Your Highness. He is my enemy. The one that loses the fight, dies.”

“That…”

Her Highness collapsed to her knees on the spot, and began to mutter something, with large tears in her eyes. The look on her face was tragic.

The moment I saw her, I felt something very hot coming into my mind.

The sensation is also felt in my neck. Then there was numbness as if an electric current was being passed into me. But it doesn’t feel bad, it feels like something will come to life…

When I saw Her Highness crying again, I realized the change.

Her silver eyes turned blue, as her eyes got activated while her brilliance increased. At the same time, something came to my mind…

But before I was surprised at the change, I thought.

Oh, I can’t believe I’m making myself look like this, I’m a bad magician.

Arsenas smiled with conviction of victory, lifted the sword on my neck, and prepared to swing it down.

“Nooooooo!!”

A mournful cry.

Certainly in a few moments, the scene where my head is flying will become a reality… if I didn’t do anything.

“It’s all right, Your Highness… no, Richena. I’ve already laid the foundation.”

I said so, and Arsenas frowned suspiciously just as the light passed.

“Gua… ugh!”

Fresh blood flying in the air. I hit it.

Arsenas drops his swinging sword and turns around in the direction of the air that has just opened a hole in his arm. He opened his eyes in astonishment.

“This!”

“Did I use magic only to hit you in a straight line without thinking? That’s not the case, is it?”

What I was looking at was the magic I used earlier, which froze the wall of a house with ice crystals. In addition, it’s a finger light bullet that I fired in rapid succession and he countered!

I froze and fixed my bent legs to jump away. I won’t miss it.

“You said it, didn’t you? That you fight in the best way according to the situation and place. It doesn’t seem to apply to you…”

“Well, you idiot… I can do that.”

“Unfortunately…”

I got up and stuck out my tongue with my thumb down. It’s childish, but forgive me this once.

Because I had just won the battle of my life.

“The opponent was bad. I’m a sniper, who wields magic in any situation or terrain.”

A number of light bullets reflecting from the ice mirror attacked Arsenas, who had become defenseless.

I was precise, but I aimed to strike at non vital points. He dropped his sword and couldn’t escape.

I can relax my mind because I have won, I’m sure my opponent can’t do anything anymore. He was attacked at the speed of light from an unexpected location. There’s no way to prevent it!

“Ack – haa”

Arsenas was punctured, vomited blood, fell down, and was unable to move.

I also feel like lying down like that…

No, I have to lie down and rest. But that’s going to be a little later.

I have to comfort Richena who ran up to me and hugged me.

“… I’m… hoo… okay… Are you okay…”

“I’m sorry. It’s more difficult than I thought. I made you worry.”

I kept patting her head. I’m worried that her clothes might get dirty with my blood… but if I ask her to leave here, she’ll get angry. It’s almost time for the royal family to start speaking, so I have to go to the royal palace as soon as possible. I have to treat my wound, or rather worse. The place where I was stabbed is vital, and I can still see the bleeding even though it has subsided a lot from other cuts. My skin is paler than usual.

“First of all, heal the wound with healing magic…”

When I put my hand on the wound in my abdomen and tried to give it a simple treatment, a warm light enveloped my whole body.

This… They came earlier than I expected.

“Oh, you’re just right on time. Milena-san, I was just dying.”

“What are you trying to die for? There’s still a lot of work to do.”

“No, please worry a little.”

“Yes, I was worried. Our workload will increase.”

That’s terrible. I can’t believe this reaction when you see your injured subordinates… Is it really a wrong choice to get this job? I’d appreciate it if you could heal my wound.

But, it’s great to be free of pain. Finally…

“But I honestly admire you for completing your mission. Well done.”

“Thank you very much. Milena-san’s coming here means that it’s over now. Have the zombie soldiers been cleared up?”

“Yes, almost. Elto-san and Arina-san cleaned it up in about 3 minutes. Including the ambush that was planned in the alleys of the city.”

“You finish work too early…”

It would have been better if either of them had escorted her, not me. They will probably take 2 minutes to finish Arsenas at most.

“Well, I’ll send Her Highness to the Royal Palace, and it’ll be over. Right, it’s finally over. I’ll go home early and have some tea — “

“I said almost, right?”

“Is there anything left?”

“Rather than anything left…you could say that there was a new problem.”

New problem… zombie soldiers sprang up again? Then, leave it to those two… I thought, but Milena-san crossed her arms and ordered me.

“It’s an additional mission. You’re going to kill the dangerous species that appeared in the south of the royal capital – Ortros. There is no veto. You have to clean it up in less than a few minutes, can you?”

“… Yes.”

Please refer to the dictionary for tyranny, chief.

Epilogue: The Plot of Her Highness’ Failed Kidnapping

The plot aimed at and carried out on the once a year festival day called the Founding Festival was resolved behind the scenes with the Royal Annihilation Force playing a leading role through the great efforts of its magicians.

Because of the efforts of the Royal Chivalric Order, the corpses wearing imperial guard uniforms left downtown, part of the houses during the battle that were destroyed and so forth were recovered without making the situation public.

Of course, “with this everything was resolved” is not what I’m saying.

The identity of the mastermind who killed imperial guard members and turned them into zombie soldiers, and a detailed explanation of the magical formula engraved on those troops and magical beasts’ hearts were needed.

And above all else, the mystery of the person Arsenas called master. From this incident, it became necessary to confirm the existence of those who resented the kingdom and work out immediate countermeasures.

The Imperial Court Magicians from here on would resolve the fundamentals of the event in addition to improve their abilities and so forth, with every day becoming busy without breaks.

一For now, the plot did not become public, the royal family’s speech finished successfully, and the Founding Festival came to an end.

Then several days later──

◇

A certain day’s early afternoon.

Elt-san and I sat side by side on a bench placed in the royal palace’s garden and talked about the matter of the Founding Festival from a few days ago.

“By the way, how did you defeat the vice captain of the imperial guards?”

“I survived. More or less.”

“More or less? What does that mean?”

I shrugged in response to Elt-san raising his eyebrows in a puzzled way.

“I say more or less, but that doesn’t mean him becoming a human in a vegetative state. Milena-san used some kind of magic to break the magic on him. The detailed effects will be studied later, from what I know. He hasn’t come to his senses yet.”

“Even if the magic was broken, he made your body full of holes, right? You survived well.”

“I was originally aiming to avoid hits to the vitals.  Moreover, with the addition of Milena’s special healing magic, I thought he’d come to his senses without any obstacles.”

“No, it was better if it was hitting by reflecting, but adjusting the line of fire to avoid hits to the vitals……what skill. There are a lot of problems with the angles of reflection and so on……”

“As for that, look, I’m a sniper.”

“That’s not the reason why!”

I felt a light impact on my forehead. A sudden finger flick to the forehead hurts……

I filled my mouth with a sandwich in one go, chewed, swallowed, and leaned against the back of the chair

“There are still problems remaining, but I think we’ve reached a point where we can rest.”

“No, I think there are still problems remaining.”

“? What is──ah”

Elt-san turned towards a direction──when he turned his gaze towards the fountain built in the center, he showed a vague smile. (TL: It is unclear whether this second part is referring to Elt or MC)

I see. There was still one large problem remaining.

“Did you mess up somehow?”

“I didn’t do anything like that……probably.”

“Then why──does Her Highness always stare at you……”

In my line of sight──in the shadow of the water fountain, Her Highness was hiding and staring in my direction──Rishena-sama had come. When the sun’s light shined, her beautiful silver hair glittered brilliantly. She was beautiful as always.

“……Since the guard incident from before, you’ve been hiding in the shadows and watching me like that almost every day, haven’t you? What is it? Go there and say it like I did.

“Even if I asked that……”

“It’s obvious that she’s watching, so why don’t you go and ask her directly?”

“No, I couldn’t do that without having no important matters to start a conversation……”

I had an escort mission before, so I was able to talk to her, but now there are no circumstances like that. We have returned to the position of being a princess and commoner magician.

To be honest, there are things I want to talk about that would be nice.

Or rather, there is one important matter──at that time, what did she mutter? And also, the sparkle in her eyes. I guessed that was probably the reason my Geas was released, but since Her Highness forbid me from asking that question, I couldn’t help but obey. But I really want to get that information out of her badly. (TL: As a reminder, the Geas is the oath that makes these destructive magicians forget the names of the royal family, I will be calling it that from now on)

Ah, our eyes met. I smiled and bowed lightly.

She returned the bow with a smile, even though her face turned red slightly.

……I wonder what it is. It seems like the tiredness in my mind is being healed. A pleasant feeling that purified my daily mental fatigue all at once. To say the least, it’s an incredibly beautiful angelic smile. Thank you.

And while I was being healed alone, Rishena-sama ran away at full speed like before.

“……Well, living your youth is the most important thing.”

“What do you mean?”

“You’ll understand soon.”

Saying that, Elt-san finished his lunch and left. I didn’t know the meaning of his sigh before leaving, but even if I asked, he’d just dodge the question, so I didn’t ask.

Anyway, the last remaining problem……well, I generally guessed what it was. It was the scene from earlier.

──Recently, I’ve been concerned about the princess staring at me.

Will a time when this problem is resolved come?

While thinking about this doubt, I finished eating the sandwich.

Afterword

With this, section one is now complete.

To everyone who read, I truly thank you very much.

I’m still inexperienced, so I think there were a lot of poor-quality parts. I apologize for that.

I’m thinking about the story from section two on, so I’m going to stop updating daily temporarily.   Sorry.